Guide to the Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory records, 1958-2000.
Arecibo Ionospheric Observatory records
- Series V. Publications
  - News Articles
    - Sky & Telescope - Letter to the Editor, Arecibo Misinformation, 10/17/1985 (Box 53, Folder 141)
    - Princeton University - "New Millisecond Pulsar Discovered in Binary Orbit", 1/15/1986 (Box 53, Folder 142)
    - Inaugurated use of a new H1000 computer system at Arecibo Observatory, 3/14/1986 (Box 53, Folder 143)
    - Cornell University News - Harris Corp. gives Arecibo Observatory $324K in computer hardware/software, 3/14/1986 (Box 53, Folder 144)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Improvements urged for Arecibo" (Roger Segelken), 10/23/1986 (Box 53, Folder 145)
    - Hagfors re: misinformation in high school textbook, 11/18/1986 (Box 53, Folder 146)
    - San Francisco Examiner - "Astronomers 'snap' first photo of asteroid" (Keay Davidson), 12/13/1986 (Box 53, Folder 147)
    - Science News - "Ghost pulsars in the sky", 1986 (Box 53, Folder 148)
    - "Saying Hello to the Stars" (Bill Keir), 1986 or 87? (Box 53, Folder 149)
    - Cornell University News - "Mysterious interstellar lenses allowing astronomers to see pulsar depths", 2/1/1988 (Box 53, Folder 150)
    - Cornell Daily Sun - "Astronomers Improve Telescope Resolution" (John Metzler), 2/2/1988 (Box 53, Folder 150.1)
    - IAU Circular - "110-ms Pulsar in M15" (Alex Wolszczan), 2/22/1988 (Box 53, Folder 151)
    - El Mundo - "NASA hara pruebas en Arecibo", 3/22/1988 (Box 53, Folder 151.1)
    - Princeton University - "Physicists Discover Dwarf Star", 4/4/1988 (Box 53, Folder 152)
    - San Juan Star - "Gateway to the universe" (Bob McCoy), 4/17/1988 (Box 53, Folder 153)
    - San Juan Star Magazine - "Reaching for the Stars", 4/17/1988 (Box 53, Folder 154)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Strange duo discovered in space: spinning pulsar with lightweight companion" (Dennis Meredith), 5/3/1988 (Box 53, Folder 155)
    - New York Times - "Shrinking Companion for Very Fast Pulsar" (Walter Sullivan), 5/10/1988 (Box 53, Folder 156)
    - Sky & Telescope - "U.S. Astronomy in Crisis", May-88 (Box 53, Folder 157)
    - The Scientist - "Astronomers suffer from decade of funding neglect", 8/8/1988 (Box 53, Folder 158)
    - Discover - "The Eclipsing Death Star-A pulsar is caught in the act of destroying its stellar companion" (Richard Preston", Aug-88 (Box 53, Folder 159)
    - The Seven Graphic Arts - "Anybody out there?" (F. Golden), 9/8/1988 (Box 53, Folder 160)
    - World Monitor - "Astronomers in the Dark" (A. Lightman), Nov-88 (Box 53, Folder 161)
    - Physics Today - Hagfors & Giovanelli correspondence re: article "An Astronishing Pulsar", Jan-89 (Box 53, Folder 162)
    - The Boston Globe - "Discovery of 2 stars may offer clues on the pulsar and its prey" (David L. Chandler), 1/10/1989 (Box 53, Folder 163)
    - Science News - "Puzzling pulses from a star cluster's core", Feb-89 (Box 53, Folder 164)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Federal budget cuts imperil upgrading of Arecibo" (Dennis Meredith), 2/16/1989 (Box 53, Folder 165)
    - Mathematical Ideas - "Pulsar eclipse", 4/19/1989 (Box 53, Folder 166)
    - San Juan Star - "Arecibo hosts scientist for meteor study" (Beatriz de la Torre), 5/14/1989 (Box 53, Folder 167)
    - Sky & Telescope - "Improvements for Arecibo", May-89 (Box 53, Folder 168)
    - San Juan Star - "The cowboy astronomers of Arecibo" (Beatriz de la Torre), 5/28/1989 (Box 53, Folder 169)
    - P.M. Magazin - Serie Relativitat, Jun-89 (Box 53, Folder 170)
    - Cornell University News - "Speed of New Pulsar's Spin Invalidates Basic Theory, Cornell Scientist Say" (Dennis Meredith), 8/9/89 (Box 53, Folder 170.1)
    - Cornell University News - "Astronomers discover first nearby protogalaxy" (Dennis Meredith), 8/25/1989 (Box 53, Folder 171)
    - New York Times - "Birth of Galaxy Seen in Gas Cloud" (Philip J. Hilts), 8/29/1989 (Box 53, Folder 172)
    - San Juan Star - "Astronomers' accidental find hailed as a 'birth of a galaxy'" (Ian Simpson), 8/30/1989 (Box 53, Folder 173)
    - NSF News - "Astronomers Discover Hydrogen Cloud that may be Unborn Galaxy", 8/29/1989 (Box 53, Folder 174)
    - Cornell Daily Sun - "Cornell Astronomers Discuss Protogalaxy" (Peter Routman), 8/31/1989 (Box 53, Folder 175)
    - Australian Telescope brochure - Radio telescopes, Sep-89 (Box 53, Folder 176)
    - Cornell Daily Sun - "Hurricane Hugo Thretnes CU's Arecibo Observatory" (Peter Routman), 9/19/89 (Box 53, Folder 176.1)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Arecibo yields insights into Venus' surface" (Dennis Meredith), 11/2/89 (Box 53, Folder 176.2)
    - Caltech/JPL/NASA press - Newly discovered asteroid, 1989 P.B., 11/20/1989 (Box 53, Folder 177)
    - NSF News - "First views of small asteroid reveal double-lobed object" (Cheryl Dybas), 11/21/1989 (Box 53, Folder 178)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Arecibo images of asteroid show double body", Nov-89 (Box 53, Folder 179)
    - West Publishing Co. - Arecibo radar image of Venus in Understanding the Universe, 3/8/1990 (Box 53, Folder 180)
    - Chance: New Directions for Statistics & Computing - "Chatting with Exterrestrials - What are the Odds?" (Tony Hoffman), Spring 1990 (Box 53, Folder 181)
    - Cornell University News - "Arecibo astronomer discovers precise "cosmic clock" in outer space", 4/25/1991 (Box 53, Folder 182)
    - Ithaca Journal - "CU scientist sees Venus through Magellan's eyes" (John Yaukey), 5/8/1991 (Box 53, Folder 183)
    - Ithaca Journal - "Feds to spend $23M to upgrade CU telescope" (John Yaukey), 5/8/1991 (Box 53, Folder 184)
    - Cornell University News - "First Metal Asteroid Discovered by Scientists At Arecibo" (Dennis Meredith), 6/7/1991 (Box 53, Folder 184.1)
    - Chicago Sun-Times - "Asteroid totes a mother lode" (Curt Suplee), 6/7/1991 (Box 53, Folder 185)
    - The Denver Post - "Far-out lode - Gold, platinum asteroid discovered" (Curt Suplee), 6/7/1991 (Box 53, Folder 186)
    - Cornell University News - "Ancient neutron star has planets, and others may, too: Arecibo-Cornell Astronomer" (Roger Segelken), 1/8/1992 (Box 53, Folder 187)
    - New York Times - "Evidence Grows Stronger for Planets Orbiting Exploded Star" (John Noble Wilford), 1/9/1992 (Box 53, Folder 188)
    - Washington Post - "Scientists Find Clear Signs of Planets Around a Dead Star" (Kathy Sawyer), 1/9/1992 (Box 53, Folder 189)
    - Atlanta Constitution - "Telescope bust turns into boon in space" (Mike Toner), 1/14/1992 (Box 53, Folder 190)
    - Science News - "Radio Pulses Hint at Unseen Planets" (R. Cowen), 1/14/1992 (Box 53, Folder 190.1)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Astronomer discovers planets around pulsar" (Roger Segelken), 1/16/1992 (Box 53, Folder 191)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Planet discover becomes international news story" (Roger Segelken), 1/16/1992 (Box 53, Folder 192)
    - New York Times - "Astronomer Retracts His Discovery of Planet" (John Noble Wilford), 1/16/1992 (Box 53, Folder 192.1)
    - Science - "Have Astronomers Bagged a Pair of Pulsar Planets?" (Faye Flam), 1/17/1992 (Box 53, Folder 193)
    - The Boston Globe - "New Planets Likely to be First of Many" (David L. Chandler), 1/20/1992 (Box 53, Folder 194)
    - San Jose Mercury - "A Solar System is Born" (Peter Weiss), 2/18/1992 (Box 53, Folder 195)
    - Weekly Reader - "U.S. Searches for Life in Outer Space", 4/10/1992 (Box 53, Folder 196)
    - San Juan Star - "Nike-Tomahawk rocket launch postponed for 4th straight night" (P.J. Ortiz), 5/22/1992 (Box 53, Folder 197)
    - Cornell University News - "Astronomers accurately measure velocities of binary galaxies" (Larry Bernard), 6/11/1992 (Box 53, Folder 198)
    - Cornell University News - "Sounding rockets investigate ionosphere with help from Arecibo" (Larry Bernard), Jun-92 (Box 53, Folder 198.1)
    - Discover - "SPACE: Looking for Trash", Jul-92 (Box 53, Folder 199)
    - Life Magazine - "The Search for a Real E.T.", Sep-92 (Box 53, Folder 200)
    - SETI News - "NASA Search Begins! Targeted Search Starts at Arecibo" (Seth Shostak), 4th Qtr 1992 (Box 53, Folder 200.1)
    - Cornell University News - "Arecibo set to begin search for extraterrestrial signals, as telescope upgrade begins" (Larry Bernard), 10/8/1992 (Box 54, Folder 201)
    - Cornell University News - "Improvements to make Arecibo Observatory more powerful, sensitive" (Larry Bernard), 10/9/1992 (Box 54, Folder 202)
    - San Juan Star - "Arecibo search under way for life among the stars", 10/13/1992 (Box 54, Folder 203)
    - New York Times - "Astronomers start search for life beyond Earth" (John Noble Wilford), 10/13/1992 (Box 54, Folder 204)
    - Cornell Daily Sun - "Telescopes search for alien life" (Chris Goffard), 10/15/1992 (Box 54, Folder 205)
    - NSF News - "Improvements to Arecibo Observatory to make telescope more powerful" (Cheryl Dybas), 10/26/1992 (Box 54, Folder 206)
    - Cornell Daily Sun - "Jill Tarter '66: Exploring the Final Frontier" (Jeanne Whalen), 2/17/1993 (Box 54, Folder 207)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Astronomers discover fastest star ever" (Larry Bernard), 3/11/1993 (Box 54, Folder 208)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Astronomy center chief didn't always look to the stars" (Larry Bernard), 4/8/1993 (Box 54, Folder 208.1)
    - Dialoo (Univ. of Puerto Rico) - "Brilla el talento de pais…" (Gerardo Cordero), Aug-93 (Box 54, Folder 209)
    - Carnival Currents - "E.T., We're Listening" (Frederic Golden), Winter 1993 (Box 54, Folder 210)
    - Omni Magazine - "An Ear to the Heavings: Improvements to Arecibo could mean dazzling discoveries" (Steve Nadis), Dec-93 (Box 54, Folder 211)
    - Physics Today - "Hulse and Taylor win Nobel Prize for Discovering Binary Pulsar" (Bertram Schwarzschild), Dec-93 (Box 54, Folder 212)
    - National Geographic - Lending an Ear, pg 39 -41, Jan-94 (Box 54, Folder 212.1)
    - USA Today - "Three planets found outside solar system" (Tim Friend), 4/22/1994 (Box 54, Folder 213)
    - Ithaca Journal - "CU telescope braces for Hurricane Luis" (John Yaukey), 1/6/1995 (Box 54, Folder 213.1)
    - Houston Chronicle - "Ice on moon turns into hot prospect" (Carlos Byars), 3/14/1995 (Box 54, Folder 214)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "James Bond casts 'Goldeneye" on Arecibo Observatory" (, 12/7/1995 (Box 54, Folder 215)
    - American Way - "Star Search: Hitting the high point of Puerto Rico -- would you believe a telescope?" (Sallie Tisdale), 2/1/1996 (Box 54, Folder 216)
    - Chronicle of Higher Education - "Scientists Listen for Intelligent Life" (Kim A. McDonald), 3/1/1996 (Box 54, Folder 216.1)
    - Ithaca Journal - "Arecibo will soon be more powerful" (John Yaukey), 5/22/1996 (Box 54, Folder 217)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Arecibo Observatory's upgrade nears completion" (Larry Bernard), 5/23/1996 (Box 54, Folder 218)
    - Science - "Upgrade to improve Arecibo's Vision" (James Glanz), 5/31/1996 (Box 54, Folder 219)
    - Sky & Telescope - "Arecibo Upgrade on Course", Aug-96 (Box 54, Folder 220)
    - IEEE Potentials - "The Second Arecibo Upgrade" (Paul F. Goldsmith), Aug/Sep 1996 (Box 54, Folder 221)
    - Science News Online - "The Big Question: Giant ears await alien broadcasts" (Erik Skindrud), 9/7/1996 (Box 54, Folder 221.1)
    - Cornell Daily Sun - "Signals from Outer Space" (Jennifer Chen), 11/21/1996 (Box 54, Folder 222)
    - Nature - "Radiotelescopes face costs of complexity", 12/12/1996 (Box 54, Folder 223)
    - NAIC News - Compilation of news articles from 1996-2002, 1996-2002 (Box 54, Folder 224)
    - The Ithaca Journal - "Telescope contractor sues Cornell for $7M" (John Yaukey), 1/14/1997 (Box 54, Folder 225)
    - Connections, Cornell School of EE - "Arecibo Observatory Completes Upgrade" (Tor Hagfors), Spring 1997 (Box 54, Folder 226)
    - SETI News - Carl Sagan died 12/20/96, 1st Qtr 1997 (Box 54, Folder 226.1)
    - Cornell University News - "Media dat at Arecibo Observatory is Friday, June 13", 4/3/97 (Box 54, Folder 226.2)
    - Cornell Magazine - "Eye on the Universe" (Beth Saulnier), May/June 1997 (Box 54, Folder 227)
    - New York Times - "New Findings Cast Doubts on Possibility of Lunar Ice" (William J. Broad), 6/6/1997 (Box 54, Folder 227.1)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Radar mapping of moon shows no evidence of ice" (Larry Bernard), 6/12/1997 (Box 54, Folder 228)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Upgrade to the Arecibo Observatory will be dedicated on Saturday" (Larry Bernard), 6/12/1997 (Box 54, Folder 229)
    - Nature - "Arecibo enters 'new era' in astronomy" (Steve Nadis), 6/12/1997 (Box 54, Folder 230)
    - San Juan Star - "Arecibo receives new Gregorian telescope" (Juan A. Hernandez), 6/15/1997 (Box 54, Folder 231)
    - Le Figaro - "Le cosmos est sous e'coute" (Fabrice Node'-Langlois), 6/16/1997 (Box 54, Folder 232)
    - New York Times - "A Once-Mighty Radiotelescope Moves Back to the Cutting Edge" (Malcolm W. Browne), 6/17/1997 (Box 54, Folder 233)
    - The Ithaca Journal - "Sky's the limit on what upgraded Arecibo will reveal" (John Yaukey), 6/18/1997 (Box 54, Folder 234)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Arecibo Observatory, even more powerful and sensitive, is dedicated" (Larry Bernard), 6/19/1997 (Box 54, Folder 235)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Success of Arecibo radar telescope depends on pinpoint accuracy" (William Steele), 6/19/1997 (Box 54, Folder 236)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "You don't need a telescope to find interesting information at Arecibo" (Blaine P. Friedlander Jr.), 6/19/1997 (Box 54, Folder 237)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Some facts (and a little history) about Arecibo", 6/19/1997 (Box 54, Folder 238)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Observatory's new visitors center combines education and research" (William Steele), 6/19/1997 (Box 54, Folder 239)
    - Science - "Arecibo's More Sensitive Eye on the Sky" (Charles Seife), 6/20/1997 (Box 54, Folder 240)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "SETI Institute's Tarter is a true Cornellian, a pioneer and a dreamer" (Linda Grace-Kobas), 6/26/1997 (Box 54, Folder 241)
    - New York Times - "Cost of Wide Phone Service May be Astronomer Static" (Malcolm W. Browne), 6/29/1997 (Box 54, Folder 241.1)
    - l'astronomia - "Arecibo la terza vita del gigante" (Riccardo Giovanelli), July 1997 (Box 54, Folder 242)
    - Engineering & Science, Caltech - "Radar Observations of Earth-Approaching Asteroids" (Steven J. Ostro), July 1997 (Box 54, Folder 243)
    - The Ithaca Journal - "Listening to the Secrets of the Universe" & "Upgraded Arecibo may reveal more" (John Yaukey), 7/5/1997 (Box 54, Folder 244)
    - New York Times - "In 'Contact,' Science and Fiction Nudge Close Together" (John Noble Wilford), 7/20/1997 (Box 54, Folder 244.1)
    - Cornell Workplace - "Dishing Out More About the Big Dish" (George Peter), 8/14/1997 (Box 54, Folder 244.2)
    - Connecting with Cornell - "The New Arecibo Observatory Opens New Worlds" (Larry Bernard), Fall 1997 (Box 54, Folder 245)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Cornell rocket experiment studies the ionosphere" (Blaine P. Friedlander Jr.), 11/20/1997 (Box 54, Folder 246)
    - IBEW Journal - "Telescopes: Tools for Studying the Electromagnetic Spectrum", Dec 1997 (Box 54, Folder 247)
    - El Nuevo Dia - "Falsa salida del Coqui II", 2/12/98 (Box 54, Folder 248)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "New pact protests Arecibo radio astronomy frequency from interference" (Lynn Simarski), 3/18/98 (Box 54, Folder 249)
    - New York Times - "Motorola and Astronomers Agree to a Time Share in Space" (Malcolm W. Browne), 3/20/1998 (Box 54, Folder 250)
    - Science - "Motorola to Limit Signals Over Arecibo" (Dana Mackenzie), 3/27/1998 (Box 54, Folder 250.1)
    - Sky & Telescope - "Bringing the Stars to the People" (D.R. Altschuler), May-98 (Box 54, Folder 251)
    - Sky & Telescope - "Arecibo and Iridium Agree to Share the Airwaves", Jun-98 (Box 54, Folder 251.1)
    - NASA News - "SOHO Spacecraft located with ground-based radar", 7/27/98 (Box 54, Folder 251.2)
    - New York Times - "Spacecraft, Once Missing, is Found" (Warren E. Leary), 7/29/98 (Box 54, Folder 251.3)
    - San Juan Star - "Lost NASA satellite found by staff at Arecibo Observatory" (Francisco Quinones), 8/08/98 (Box 54, Folder 252)
    - The Universe (Time-Life Books) - "Radio Telescopes", Sep 1998 (Box 54, Folder 253)
    - Travel Weekly - "Clients can check out the celestial at new facility", 9/28/1998 (Box 54, Folder 254)
    - New York Times - "Astronomers Revive Scan of the Heavens for Signs of Life" (William J. Broad), 9/29/1998 (Box 54, Folder 255)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Arecibo Observatory and campus relief fund assist hurricane victims" (Blaine P. Friedlander Jr.), 10/15/1998 (Box 54, Folder 256)
    - Cornell Pawprint - "Employee Assembly Arecibo Relief Effort Builds Steam", 10/22/1998 (Box 54, Folder 257)
    - Cornell Pawprint - "Arecibo Fund Drive Passes Halfway Point", 11/5/1998 (Box 54, Folder 258)
    - New York Times - "Downloading Data, in Search of Intelligent Life" (Henry Fountain), 12/8/1998 (Box 54, Folder 259)
    - "Arecibo Survives Hurricane Georges", Jan-99 (Box 54, Folder 260)
    - New York Times - "Feet Planted in Berkeley, Eyes Fixed on the Sky" (Evelyn Nieves), 04/20/99 (Box 54, Folder 261)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Undergrad David Kaplan wins prestigious Hertz Foundation award" (Susan Lang), 4/22/1999 (Box 54, Folder 262)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "CU astronomers: Views of moon's poles show potential for ice deposits" (David Brand), 6/17/1999 (Box 54, Folder 263)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "CU hosts major space conference here July 26-30" (David Brand), 7/8/1999 (Box 54, Folder 264)
    - Cornell University News - "Dramatic, close-up radar images of asteroids to be shown at international space conference at Cornell" (David Brand), 7/20/1999 (Box 54, Folder 265)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Possible Earth-asteroid collisions are a topic at CU conference session" (David Brand), 7/22/1999 (Box 54, Folder 266)
    - Ithaca Journal - "Asteroids may assist future space travel" (Missy Globerman), 7/27/1999 (Box 54, Folder 267)
    - Cornell News Release - "Most-detailed images yet of an Earth-crossing asteroid are obtained by Arecibo and, 8/26/1999 (Box 54, Folder 268)
    - New York Times - "Tumbling, Tumbling Asteroid", 8/31/1999 (Box 54, Folder 269)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Telescopes reveal detailed images of nearby asteroid" (Blaine Friedlander Jr.), 9/2/1999 (Box 54, Folder 270)
    - Ithaca Journal - "Radar advances help map asteroids" (Missy Globerman), 9/4/1999 (Box 54, Folder 271)
    - Sky & Telescope - "SETI@home: Catching the Wave" (Alan M. MacRobert & Andrew J. LePage), Oct-99 (Box 54, Folder 272)
    - Ithaca Journal - "Cornell yet to receive response from space", Nov-99 (Box 54, Folder 273)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "It's the 25th Anniversary of Earth's first (and only) attempt to phone E.T." (Bill Steele), 11/11/99 (Box 54, Folder 274)
    - Cornell Daily Sun - "Years after sending signal, astronomers await a response" (Elizabeth Itzkowitz), 11/18/99 (Box 54, Folder 275)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Jill Cornell Tarter plans new array of dishes to search for life in space" (Linda Grace-Kobas), 12/09/99 (Box 54, Folder 276)
    - Cornell University News - "Astronomers to meet in Puerto Rico to plan world's largest radio telescope - SKA", 2/8/2000 (Box 54, Folder 277)
    - Science News Online - "Owners of home computers join researchers in cracking problems and crunching data" (I. Peterson), 3/4/2000 (Box 54, Folder 277.1)
    - Space.com - "SETI: Celebrating 40 Years of Watching the Skies" (Maia Weinstock), 4/8/2000 (Box 54, Folder 278)
    - CNN.com - "NASA unveils images of giant 'dog bone' asteroid", 5/5/2000 (Box 54, Folder 278.1)
    - Ithaca Journal - "Dog-bone shaped asteroid spotted from CU facility", 5/6/2000 (Box 54, Folder 279)
    - Los Angeles Times - "Asteroid is a bone of contention for scientists", 5/6/2000 (Box 54, Folder 280)
    - Space.com - "Arecibo: Listening to the Skies" (Frederic Castel), 5/8/2000 (Box 54, Folder 280.1)
    - New York Times - "Dream On, Canis Major", 5/9/2000 (Box 54, Folder 281)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Arecibo captures radar images of giant, dog bone-shaped asteroid Kleopatra", 5/11/2000 (Box 54, Folder 282)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "New Shelley awards given to two students in astronomy", 6/8/2000 (Box 54, Folder 283)
    - El Nuevo Dia - "Experimento con auroras en Arecibo", 7/23/2000 (Box 54, Folder 284)
    - Vida Digital - "Espiando al espacio desde el patio de Arecibo", Nov-00 (Box 54, Folder 285)
    - Cornell Magazine - "Slam dunk", Nov/Dec 2000 (Box 54, Folder 286)
    - Astronomy.com - "Astronomy's Radio Giants Join Forces" (Vanessa Thomas), 5/12/01 (Box 54, Folder 286.1)
    - CNN - "Potent telescope pair penetrates shroud of Venus" (Richard Stenger), 5/14/2001 (Box 54, Folder 287)
    - Astronomy.com - "Near-Earth Asteroid is a Double" (Vanessa Thomas), 5/26/2001 (Box 54, Folder 287.1)
    - El Nuevo Dia - "Pobre la educacion cientifica en la isla" (Frances Rosario), 5/27/2001 (Box 54, Folder 287.2)
    - JPL Press Release - "Near-Earth Asteroid is Two Chunks in One" (Martha J. Heil), 5/30/2001 (Box 54, Folder 288)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Cornell astronomers use the Arecibo Observatory to reveal radio beacons, called OH megamasers, that yield galactic clues" (Blaine Friedlander), 6/5/2001 (Box 54, Folder 289)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "CU astronomers use Arecibo telescope to detect objects that may yield clues to galactic formation" (Blaine P. Friedlander Jr.), 6/14/2001 (Box 54, Folder 290)
    - A Conocer a Puerto Rico - "Radio telescopio de Arecibo Obra Universal de la Ingenieria y la Agrimensura" (Carlos Colon), 7/1/2001 (Box 54, Folder 290.1)
    - Science News - "Bow-wowing them with radar", 7/28/2001 (Box 54, Folder 291)
    - New York Times - "Interference from a Noisy Planet" (Christine Kenneally), 8/21/2001 (Box 54, Folder 292)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Capital Hill staff visit Arecibo Observatory", 8/30/2001 (Box 54, Folder 293)
    - Electronic Design Staff Report - "40 years ago: Design on Areibo Radar on Schedule" (Steve Scrupski), Sep 2001 (Box 54, Folder 294)
    - Mercury - "Pas de Deux" (Marcia Bartusiak), Sep/Oct 2001 (Box 54, Folder 295)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Arecibo Observatory will receive a prestigious award at Nov. 3 ceremony" (David Brand), 11/01/01 (Box 54, Folder 296)
    - IEEE Press Release - "Arecibo Observatory Declared IEEE Milestone in Electrical Engineering", 11/3/2001 (Box 54, Folder 297)
    - Astronomy.com - "More Asteroids Pair Up" (Vanessa Thomas), 11/10/2001 (Box 54, Folder 297.1)
    - Astronomy.com - "Close Call for NEO Research" (Vanessa Thomas), 12/21/2001 (Box 54, Folder 297.2)
    - Cornell News Release - "Rollin' down the river: Arecibo Observatory captures evidence of turbulence and thick gas as a possible precursor to galactic evolution" (Blaine P. Friedlander Jr.), 1/9/2002 (Box 54, Folder 298)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Arecibo evidence of galactic turbulence may yield star-formation clues" (Blaine Friedlander), 1/17/2002 (Box 54, Folder 298.1)
    - Science Daily.com - "Arecibo Observatory Captures Evidence of Turbulence and Thick Gas as a Possible Precursor to Galactic Evolution", 1/23/2002 (Box 54, Folder 299)
    - Astronomy.com - "The Stealthy Bright Side of Iapetus" (Ralph D. Lorenz), 2/6/2002 (Box 54, Folder 299.1)
    - Gran Telescopio Canarias - "Points of View: Daniel Altschuler", 2/12/2002 (Box 54, Folder 300)
    - IEEE History Center - "IEEE Milestones: NAIC/Arecibo Radiotelescope, 1963", 3/13/2002 (Box 54, Folder 300.1)
    - San Juan Star - "Arecibo Observatory: Science's 'ear' in space" (John McPhaul), 3/18/2002 (Box 54, Folder 300.2)
    - New York Times - "Supercomputing '@Home' Is Paying Off for a Variety of Scientific Research", 4/23/2002 (Box 54, Folder 301)
    - Cornell Chronicle - "Arecibo radar reveals double asteroid systems in Earth-crossing orbits" (David Brand), 5/9/2002 (Box 54, Folder 302)